[Music]
w
hello and welcome back to the asket show
the show returns after a brief Hiatus of
a couple of weeks and a lot has happened
in this time so it's great to be back
back among you all I hope you're all
doing very well I hope you didn't miss
me too much so let's see who all is
there on the live stream all right let's
see who all is there let me see I can
see swam anit KP g b 134 RK achara
inia by manil Mr macius Mimis bat
extreme alok bat Kumar
kanish uh Kushi Sharma DJ div this
the sorry I can't pronounce that subit
statement AI Himalaya Chand GI political
dub hello sakeet
katari niharika tagat airo shagun Chopra
bojac Horseman Dr Atul Ramesh muruga
Deepak jangid threat Tripper Dr suak
dager hello utar Z
IJ ABI Gad Haron V sain Mahajan prian
Patel X mus y mus
Zas Ashish vishwakarma sakit katari
midnight stalker akne Rasoi Rashmi Reika
Singh chananya B dungar Singh Chan hello
soag Das tripti Mishra Jil chandarana
chandar yes prakash paa Roshan ja netian
ragir sanki random skull rakit Mishra
and lots and lots of the people
Anonymous Imran naimi geopolitical dub
Vladimir vladimirovich Putin
shagun chobra Hello from akashwani Hello
uh Jack okay very
good um Aditya Anand suant gurer surj
and everybody else okay I'm gonna stop
there otherwise it's gonna go on forever
but yes hello welcome to all of you so
like I said a lot has happened a
tremendous amount of stuff has happened
I just go away for a couple of weeks and
so much happens Donald Trump almost gets
taken out 19
63 those of you who have watched my
previous live streams will remember that
I have said multiple times there is a
chance there's a possibility that Donald
Trump would get
1963 in case you don't know what 1963
it's the year that uh John F Kennedy was
taken
out uh by an unknown shooter allegedly
so I had said I have said this multiple
times that it could happen and it almost
happens he was lucky he was really lucky
that he didn't didn't die and then
there's the new there's a resumption of
the Israel Iran thing
yeah uh and and so much more someone
saying that saying that I look good on
short hair well I still have long hair
by the way but all right thank you so so
much has happened okay so uh please ask
me your questions the Paris Olympics are
going on very interesting weird Olympics
are going on and so much
more so please go ahead ask me your
questions and let's take some questions
come on so there's a question by somi
Jen who said you said Trump won't come
back but if he will then it will prove
that deep state does not exist right as
they don't want him to come back well
yeah I've been asked this question many
times whether I think whether I believe
that Donald Trump will win this election
the 2024 election and I still and I've
said multiple times that I don't think
he's going to win and I still believe
that he won't win because everyone's
after him okay he's an outsider he's a
threat to the Deep establishment he's a
threat to all the
what what we call the oim the the
existing entrenched powers powers and
they won't allow him to return see the
the 2020 elections were essentially well
whether you like it or not they were
rigged okay and it's going to be much
worse this year and uh look they they
have brought in Kamala Kamala is now the
presidential candidate from the
Democratic side well where's the
Democracy in this if the incumbent
president decides not to run for
election reelection then there should be
a round of primaries right in which the
Democrats can vote for their candidate
and then that's how the next candidate
is supposed to be selected or elected
but in this case she's just been
handpicked for example the Republicans
had their primaries and Donald Trump
emerged as the most popular candidate so
the same should have happened among the
the the Democrats the happen where's the
Democracy in the US so um so I don't
think I still don't think Donald Trump
will will win this election I think it's
very unlikely very un highly unlikely he
clearly is the most popular candidate
and if there's a free and fair election
he will wipe the floor with Kamala
Harris but I don't think it's going to
happen he still good could get
1963 they may try it
again so um deep State exist on look you
can never
prove or disprove the existence or
non-existence of the deep state but uh
anybody who has any understanding of
history and who has studied the way the
United States actually operates the way
it runs Etc will understand that there
is an extra Democratic ex constitutional
Center of power somewhere in the US
maybe it's within the us maybe it's
outside maybe it's distributed maybe
it's concentrated we will not get into
those things but I think everybody today
understands that the Deep State exists
and they are that that's the shadowy
bunch of individuals who actually rules
the United States and the president is
just meant to you know divert people's
attention away from where the real power
lies uh in case you have read that book
The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy
well it deas Adam speaks about precisely
that when he when he refers to zapod
bble Brocks
anyway
um okay let's Let's uh okay here's
another question about the same thing
off says uh Trump's assassination
attempt was it the CIA was it China was
it the Democrats who was it look the
Chinese are not really I would say
capable of taking
out uh somebody who's running for US
president and even if they perhaps may
be capable in case they are they why
would they do that do that they they
would stand to risk too much I don't
think the Chinese are involved I don't
think the Russians are involved Putin
would want Mr Trump to come back to
power but uh so why would he want to
take Mr Trump
out is it the
Democrats do we have any evidence the
Democrats are involved we know that the
the this attempt at assassinating Trump
I mean there were glaring security
lapses horrible security lapses multiple
lapses I mean that the guy the shooter
people had spotted him I don't know 20
30 50 minutes before he took took his
shot and people had been alerting the
cops and the Secret Service and whatnot
and the guy was was on this roof and the
building under the roof there were
secret service in there so how on Earth
did they not discover this guy there and
that was the best firing angle
if you look at the the geography of the
region of of of the place of the spot so
it looks like the Secret Service wanted
this to happen or they were under orders
to allow this to happen that's what it
looks like now the Secret Service isn't
run by the Democrats okay the Secret
Service is uh well it's part of the US
government and uh it comes I'm not sure
what it comes under but it essentially
comes under the Deep
state so yeah I don't know look look I
can only speculate who could have been
behind this and I would speculate that
it's the it's the unelected powers that
gen that actually rule the United States
that do not want Mr Trump to come back
to Power and probably they may have been
behind this probably possibly
perhaps the same way they could have
possibly been behind what happened to Mr
Kennedy so yeah one can only speculate
because you don't really have any
evidence of
anything oh really RMS says what do you
think about the new Parliament roof leak
I wasn't aware of this is the parliament
new parliament's roof leaking that if if
that's the case then it's disappointing
truly disappointing shouldn't happen but
what can I say this is India we have
different standards compared to the rest
of the world we still have better
standards than than the French
apparently I mean we had to I just heard
five minutes before this live stream
started that the government of India had
to to send what 400 or 40 air
conditioners to France to take care of
our athletes there because the French
don't have air conditioners
apparently well
anyway Guru Prasad says will there be
any changes in diplomacy if the if an
opposition party comes to power in India
definitely our foreign policy will take
a 180 degree
U-turn 180 not 360 360 is you back come
back to the same place if an opposition
party or a coalition of opposition
parties come to come to comes to power
in India it's going to be a complete
U-turn in terms of foreign policy
everything that Mr Modi and U his uh
government have been trying to do the
past 10 years will be undone in a matter
of weeks so yeah and India's diplomacy
will hearken back to the old days in
which we will have these Craven
pusillanimous
cowardly um positions in foreign policy
we have no aspiration of being a great
power we we are happy with mediocrity
like one of our Prime Ministers had said
in not the not too long ago not Mr Modi
someone before him so yeah total change
in diplomacy will
happen Dr Atul says I guess you're aware
of the landslide situation in vard
Kerala over 400 people are dead
ridiculous terrible what are the
measures to avoid these is the Western
guts PR to these that's interesting
that's an interesting question um I
think someone asked me this today not
here but offline the same thing about
the Western carts so uh I've heard about
the landslide situation Viet I've not
seen any images I've not really looked
into the
matter it's not something that it's a
terrible tragedy
obviously uh so yes I've heard about it
400 400 plus people dead that's a
disaster and and I wonder who's
responsible for this I would say it's
the state government that's responsible
for this uh obviously the state
government has to take responsibility
when something happens within your state
because the state is is it's under your
jurisdiction uh so yeah it's it's
terrible I'm not sure why it's happened
how it's happened I don't know about the
geography in detail of that particular
specific place within Southern India so
I can't say I can't answer as to why
this happened how it happened but the
good question is this one the what are
the measures to avoid landslides so
let's understand the the the the physics
let's say the Dynamics mechanics of
landslides a landslide is what is when a
significant amount of
soil it uh slides down downhill from a
hill or a
mountain and it brings down rock and
trees and whatnot and it causes
Devastation down Downstream downhill
now why does why do landslides happen
and how do they happen they typically
happen when the soil is not strongly uh
anchored to the mountain I mean there's
a gradient there's a precipice okay
there's a certain angle at which the
mountain comes down and if the soil is
not properly anchored then it it can
become loose and it can come down
typically when it rains Etc or if it
snows but we talking about India so
mainly we're talking about rain and when
does it happen that the soil is not
firmly anchored that's when you that
happens when you have
deforestation because generally when it
comes to most parts of India we have
hills and mountains which are covered by
forests and the the trees they they
anchor the soil firmly and properly so
that it it doesn't go down when it rains
so when you have deforestation you're
going to have landslides or landslides
also occur because of earthquakes Etc
but it's mainly because of
deforestation and some landslides are
just natural even if you have forests
and even if you have trees and
vegetation so it's in some some cases a
landslide may still happen but what can
you do to prevent to avoid landslides to
prevent landslides ensure that you have
proper Forest cover wherever you have
hills and
mountains
okay uh so yeah that's what you need to
do you need to ensure that there is no
no deforestation you need to ensure that
Builders and whoever it is don't go and
start digging and cutting into the
mountains and hills with their
bulldozers because that's going to I
promise you that's going to cause
landslides long
term so we need to stop tampering with
nature we need to stop interfering with
nature you have Hills you have mountains
you let them be you don't go and mess
around with them uh don't construct too
many dams Etc too many I mean some dams
obviously we need but we have to be
judicious in the in the manner in which
we construct dams how large the dams are
and how many dams we can construct for
example if you construct 500 dams in a
mountainous uh State any any
hypothetical mountainous State then
you're going to have landslides in
earthquak and whatnot so you got to do
it judiciously we do need infrastructure
but we have to do it the right way so so
that's that's a thing uh don't cut down
forests don't uh
uh deforestation is one of the factors
very strong Factor very major factor the
other factor is when you cut cut into
the mountains to you know to extract
Rock and rubble and whatnot for
construction materials and and so on so
forth in which case you're going to have
landslides and obviously too many dams
and all that stuff can also cause
landslides are the Western CS Pro prone
to landslides not so much not as much as
other other parts of IND the Western
gats are extremely ancient mountains
very very ancient mountain range where's
the map where's the map my friends let's
find the map so where's the Western
cards where are the Western Gods so it's
a uh mountain range that uh extends all
the way essentially from Gujarat
Southern Gujarat all the way down
to uh Southern India Kerala Tamil Nadu
Etc it's a very ancient mountain range
hundreds of millions of years old and
I remember many years ago I had taken a
train
journey many years ago like closer two
decades ago I had taken a train journey
once from Mumbai to
Chennai and the train journey took two
days two days and I it was it was fun
for me I was I was looking out the
window and I could see the the hills and
the mountains and it was fascinating to
see the geology you could see the the
the the way it was stratified and all
you could see that these mountains these
Hills had once been obviously horizontal
the the straa had once been horizontal
but now they were at an angle to the
surface of the Earth and all so that
talks about very violent very powerful
geological processes that have happened
in India over time especially when India
was part of Africa then it it went over
the REO hotspot and eventually slammed
into Eurasia so all of that that history
is still visible in the western guards
the Western guards
are extremely dense in hard rock and
they are less prone to
landslides uh but yeah you mess around
with them they also you have
landslides okay next question death
killer 43 thoughts on India doing poorly
in Olympics and India winning the 2020
World 20 T20 World Cup uh how many
medals has India won thus far I think
this this lady uh shooter shooter the
shooter she has w two bronze medals and
uh someone else has won another medal
another bronze medal CNU went out I I
believe in in
badminton uh lusen or somebody was doing
well in badminton I remember uh where
were our medal hopes I'm not sure if uh
what's the guy his name the javelin
throw guy U he's he's tremendous he's
terrific so I I'm not sure if he has
competed yet I think there's a gold
medal chance there I'm not sure about
boxing and wrestling Etc what happened
there I'm not sure
so yeah it's just the way it is you know
I'll tell you what if you look at the
amount of money and resources the
Chinese government invests in sporting
activities then we are not even 100
100th of that we are somewhere around 1%
of that you know that's That's how
little our government prioritizes
sport now why would a nation like China
spend hundreds of millions I know I
would say billions of dollars in in its
sporting infrastructure in in and
investing that much money in its
athletes why would China do that because
China the Chinese government cares about
Prestige the nation's Prestige the
nation's image which is obviously
important and nothing unifies a nation
like success when you have your athletes
succeeding everywhere that unifies the
nation that gives you this feeling of
euphoria and binds everybody together
that's what every nation needs that's
why the the USSR is to invest so much in
sports that's why various European
nations invest so much in sport that's
why China invests so much in sports the
government of India has no understanding
or no interest in this they simply don't
care about National
Prestige I mean China was investing
tremendous amounts of money in in in
sport when its GDP was at the same level
as India's okay so it's not like China
started doing this when they became a
became a more powerful economy they have
been doing this for the past 20 30 years
30 years at least I think they they went
on a moratorium from the Olympics in the
1980s they said that we not participate
in the Olympics for like four or eight
years and we're going to spend that time
developing our infrastructure and and
investing in our athletes and then we're
going to come back on the on the global
stage and take the World by storm and
they did that so it's in the 80s 990s
that they were doing this and today in
India the government of India has
absolutely no interest in this the
government of India has no interest in
education in in culture in
sports we just wow in mediocrity I
promise you
this if you look at the amount of money
the Chinese are investing in their
Sports and if the same amount of money
is made available to Indian athletes in
Indian sporting infrastructure then give
India just five years and we'll be we'll
be defeating defeating the Chinese and
taking the World by storm we have
Superior at least compared to China
Superior genetics but our leadership our
our government simply doesn't have any
interest in this the nation's image the
national Prestige all of that they
simply don't care about
it so what can I say what can I say it's
tremendously disappointing we have so
much potential but the potential is just
squandered we have ministries of this
and that and what not what do the what
are what do those Ministries
do what do those Ministries do I really
wonder why those Ministries even
exist uh T20 World Cup well I'm glad we
won that whom did we defeat in the final
match I think I so some part of oh yeah
South Africa obviously yeah the catch Su
Kumar it was good to see it was good to
see so yeah I was glad that happened but
I would like to see India succeed in
other sporting disciplines as well
all right excuse
me Summit statement says I am from Nepal
and I strongly feel Indian Nationalism
but why do I struggle to see people from
syn gandhar and bangal as my own it's
disappointing that we rival a nation
once our
own yeah it's interesting right you are
from Nepal but you strongly feel the
sense of Indian Nationalism you feel the
civilizational
nationalism so to say you know we are
all part of the same civilization we are
separate Nations today but we are part
of the same civilization why do you
struggle to see people from syn gandhar
Bengal as your own well mostly Bengal
today the majority of the population is
Bangladesh right if you if you compare
the population of West Bengal with
Bangladesh Bangladesh is the larger
population and uh so maybe that's one of
the reason because Bangladesh now has a
different culture from our culture
obviously right and the same happens
when it comes to Sy and gandhar Sy and
gandhar well these were our lands you
know our our ancestor lands but they
gone now and our culture our
civilization no longer exists there so
it's it's natural to
see to to struggle to see those people
as your own because you know most people
believe that it's a the Affinity that we
we have with people is because of DNA
and blood but that's not the casee
culture is more important than DNA
culture is more important than blood so
you will feel more of a sense of
connection with somebody who shares your
culture as opposed to somebody who
shares your blood unfortunately that's
how it
goes uh so yeah that I guess that's why
you struggle to see people from these
regions as your own because they no
longer see you as your own as their own
right the people of gandar they no
longer see us Indians bhate people as
their own they they if you say that we
we were once the same people they'll
laugh at you they'll be angry they'll
say no no no we were Jews we were this
we were that we were Persians we were
Turks but we were never Indians that's
what the pashun will say most of them
today and sin Etc say same story so uh
what you are feel what you feel is the
civilizational Affinity we are part of
the same civilization all of us those of
us who still uh
practice the civilizational values and
morality and culture so I hope that in
the future we are once again unified you
know that what's the great dream that
many people have akand bhat well at
least as a civilization we can be
unified you know we can remain separate
Nations India Nepal Sri
Lanka Indonesia Thailand Burma Etc we
can remain separate Nations but we
should be unified by culture and
civilization at least we should have an
open Visa open border
regime for the
civilization closed Nations so like
India and Nepal we have open borders you
don't need the passport visa to come
into India and vice versa you can work
in India you can serving the inam forces
I would like to see the same ex be the
same kind of thing be extended to Sri
Lanka to Thailand and other nations with
reasonable security precautions Etc it
would be nice to have that eventually
Tibet as well both of
yeah so today we are fragmented because
of the uh things that happened in the
past 1,000 years but thousand years is
not a big deal for us you know we are
way older than that and we're going to
be around for at least 10,000 years more
if not us individually than our
descendants so let's let's do our best
to make things better for those who come
after us our descendants that's what we
we should
do geopolitical dub says what will
change if Trump becomes president
what will change if Trump becomes
president nothing much will change you
see um Trump was president from 2016 to
2020 what was he able to achieve in that
time period in that period of time he
did uh get the Abraham accord's done he
tried his best to to bring about peace
in Western Asia Middle East uh he tried
a lot of things he tried to Build That
Wall to keep the Mexicans out that
didn't
work so overall despite all his efforts
despite him really trying his best he
was not allowed to
succeed the entire political
establishment stood against him so what
will change if Trump becomes president
now 2024 let's say he wins the election
Against All
Odds yeah what happens what will change
I think nothing much will change I think
the same thing will happen again I'll be
I was very surprised that he was not
1963 while he was president first of all
and there's a high chance that he'll be
1963 that he may be 1963 before
re-election happens and let's say he be
he gets elected president well he's got
four years to to be in power or be in
office that might that might happen so I
don't see much changing if Trump becomes
president they will not allow him to do
the things that he wants to do they
won't allow him to achieve his
objectives
it's going to be an uphill battle every
single day for him the entire media will
go all out against him and so on unless
he has made a deal with the
devil well you know you never know
okay
okay Yash gohil says how do you remember
so such diverse data and at the same
time how do you understand or comprehend
information at the time when you're
unable or frustrated with the
information oh do I get frustrated with
information I have had so many
experiences as a student especially when
I had this Gastly textbook written by
some mediocre
author and you that was the official
textbook you had to well
study and if he did not replicate the
answers from that textbook for those
paragraphs then he would not get the
right marks and stuff so you had to just
memorize nonsense it was deeply deeply
frustrating and you learned nothing from
that you learn nothing from that it is
just an exercise in
futility so
uh so that was those were bad
experiences the Indian education system
is ghastly it's it's it's a
disaster uh and nothing has changed
nothing is changing uh but how do I
remember all this diverse data well I
read a lot okay and I only only remember
what I find interesting I have so many
books around me okay I some of these
books I've read like 17 times some books
I may have read just a few pages there
are some books over here there are more
here ET I have read an entire book which
I found interesting at the time and
today if I try to remember what was
there in the book I may struggle to
remember a single thing so it's not like
I remember everything my brain is not
like a sponge I am very forgetful I
forget like 80 90% of what I read but I
read so much and I have so many
interests and I'm so curious about about
various things that I retain maybe 5% of
it
and that's what I speak about okay um
yeah so so that's what I say so my
philosophy of reading
is it's perfectly okay if you remember
nothing if the book isn't interesting
enough if it isn't value if it isn't giv
you enough value don't read it whatever
you read it's okay to forget it that way
you'll remember what you find
interesting that's how I do
it m says I missed you so much thank you
so much I really appreciate it I am back
and now we continue continue so thank
you so much I really appreciate it I I
really
do okay Anonymous says uh could you tell
us who a Hindu is can anybody who calls
himself a Hindu become a Hindu or are
there certain practices one must do well
you know Hindu Dharma is is very diverse
um yeah it's it's that's the problem
it's so difficult to actually Define and
delineate the boundaries of what Hindu
Dharma is and who is a Hindu and who is
not it's so difficult and everybody has
a certain opinion about what a Hindu
should be like what Hinduism Hindu
Dharma is and what Hindu Dharma is not
so there is
no it is such a ancient diverse
tradition that you simp simply can't
Define
it and everybody has a different
perception different perspective there
are so many spiritual and dhic
philosophical paths in Hindu
Dharma and they are all widely different
from each other I've spoken in the past
about the various philosophical schools
of thought you know BHA Naya J mimansa
vanta charaka Etc they are so different
from each other Sanka yoga and so on so
different from each other
I mean charvaka is is atheism atheistic
materialism bodha is well it's atheistic
yes for sure it doesn't believe in a god
some people would would claim that it
doesn't believe in the existence of the
soul and so on so forth and so there is
so much diversity in what we believe in
and the kind of gods that people worship
some people have so and so is some
people have so and so other is
kulies and so many other things there
are people who have very uh you know
nature worshipping Traditions uh
ancestor worshiping traditions and so on
so so everything is allowed within the
dharmic umbrella it's very hard to to
Define from that perspective who a Hindu
is but I would say that there are
certain
values that are common in Hindu Dharma
first of all there is nonviolence so
nonviolence is preferable
it doesn't mean that you can if somebody
comes to whack you you just let it
happen no you you have to Ure the
nonviolence rules which means you to
destroy those who are violent so that's
also there uh so there are a set of
principles set of values that that are
common to all the dharmic paths and I
would say that is what Hindu Dharma is
so whether you are you know today
Hinduism Buddhism jism Etc are all
separate religions
allegedly and that's what we are taught
and now everybody grows up believing
that but if you look at the lifestyle of
of somebody who identifies as Hindu or
Buddhist or sik or whatever or Shinto
for example or
tarist they all have certain set of
values that are common I think those
values are what what defines
you what what what makes you a Hindu I
suppose okay let's not talk about Shinto
andm because people will get
upset but yeah so what are these values
well I think I have to think about it
otherwise it will take me time to
explain over here obviously nonviolence
is there uh non injury to
others um and and other things as well
so when it comes to Buddhism jism
Hinduism the lifestyle is very similar
and values are very similar so those
That's What Makes You Hindu I would say
woke Olympics yeah it's it's it's been
quite a show hasn't
it the Olympics the most incredible
Olympics one has
seen um
yeah
okay okay Pine garti says is the heart
attack to Mr sh Jinping real can we
believe
China well there was I think it was last
year or something then when people were
claiming there was a coup in China and
Mr shin had been uh ousted from Power by
the Chinese uh military the people's
Liberation Army many prominent YouTubers
and experts in India were saying this
what happened there's no CP and I had
said at the time there's no CP uh so I
don't know listen I haven't uh seen any
credible evidence of a heart attack for
Mr sh Jinping of Mr suffering a heart
attack so I would say listen let's not
speculate right now let's
buy our time let's be patient eventually
the truth will come
out that's what I would say so I don't
know I can at this point in time I can
neither say yes or no I don't know what
to what to believe because we don't have
sufficient information so let's be
patient and the truth will come out
eventually
okay Arian
says do you think the current situation
happening with Israel the US and Iran
and other included States is a master
plan of the US to create a war like
situation and postpone the elections um
interesting question interesting
interesting question so let's say there
is let's say there's a war in West Asia
okay let's go to the map where is map we
must see
map okay so we're talking about West
Asia here what they call the Middle East
Western Asia so the
the the turmoil obviously ly is always
in this region uh Iran Iraq Syria
Lebanon Israel Jordan Egypt Saudi Arabia
etc etc this region is where you
generally have turmo and it's an
everpresent factor in the geopolitics of
this region so let's say there is a war
okay we don't want a war okay we don't
want Wars we want peace but let's say
unfortunately there's a war between Iran
and
Israel so if there's a war between Iran
and Israel
will that cause a
postponement of the election
presidential election in the US I don't
think so I don't think it's going to
cause a postponement of the election
presidential election I don't think so
uh of course we know that uh this region
the fact that it's always been in
turmoil it's you know it's been caused
by external players by by great powers
in the past it was caused by the UK by
England by the British uh Empire and in
the 20th century uh post 2 World War
onwards it's typically been uh the
region has been kept a flame essentially
by the west and when we say the West we
mean NATO and when we say nato I think
we all know that we are talking about
the US so the US has kept this region in
turmoil and uh so yeah so the things
that the situation that's happening
there right now is also one could say
directly or indirectly caused by the US
the US has been a staunch supporter of
Israel uh unconditional support whatever
Israel needs the US will provide the US
will never condemn anything the Israelis
do I'm not saying that Israelis are
doing anything condemnable I'm not
saying that okay what's my perspective
in all this my perspective in what's
happening is that we Indians
there is no need for us to take sides
whenever somebody is
fighting let's say Nation X and Nation y
y x and y are fighting there a conflict
is it necessary for us Indians to take a
side in this matter is it
necessary why is it necessary it's not
necessary so my position is very clear
when it comes to all these conflicts we
are not involved in this we did not
cause the conflict we don't have a dog
in this fight we don't have a horse in
this race we will urge peace so I don't
think um the
US wants to postpone
elections and it's using this conflict
as a pretext that I don't think so
because there have been wars in the past
that's never caused a postponement of US
presidential
elections
um okay your views on China and India
relationship China is coming in hard and
prime minister M the prime minister of
India hasn't spoken much about this
look when it comes to the relationship
with China it's a it's not a good
relationship uh we haven't had good
relations with China since the
1950s okay when Mr Neu allowed the
Chinese to take over Tibet and then they
not just to not only took over Tibet but
they they they captured Indian Territory
after that so we haven't had good
relations with the Chinese ever since
that time and of late India has been
ramping up its infrastructure building
activities Etc in the Border regions
with Tibet which has uh greatly alarmed
the Chinese and that's why we've had all
these clashes the past decade or so lots
of clashes on the border we had the
galwan Clash soldiers died on both sides
and we've had other clashes also some
videos have leaked out Etc
so uh that's why the relationship isn't
good because India has been ramping up
its infrastructure building efforts um
now what's happening right now the
Chinese are coming in hard I don't see
them coming in hard what are they doing
on the border there haven't been as far
as we know any new clashes on the border
uh on the other hand there is talk of
the of the Indian government now
allowing Chinese companies to invest in
India to set up manufacturing plants in
India Etc which kind of I mean I would
be very cautious over here but it looks
like relation the relationship could
possibly perhaps
improve if both governments are okay
with
this and the fact is that the Chinese
economy is slowing down we all know that
the Chinese
need I mean there's nothing like the
Chinese getting access to a gigantic
market like India so that would be
great for the Chinese economy the
Chinese they need their economy to grow
India needs the Indian economy to grow
so let's postpone the war by five years
or so that's the kind of understanding
that we are seeing right now so India
and China as long as they share a border
unnaturally because India and China
never had a border for for 3,000 years
so as long as that as long as China is
in occupation of Tibet India and China
will never have a normal relationship
will never be friends
but right now it looks like the two
governments may have may be in the
process of thinking about agreeing to
postpone the conflict for another five
years or
something because what do we gain from a
conflict right now it's it's not a
win-win thing it's a lose lose thing um
and when it comes to the the India China
relationship the less we speak about it
the better especially from the high up
leadership so that's why the prime
minister of India will not comment much
about this and he is Justified in not
doing there's no need to comment about
everything so look the prime minister of
India we should not expect him to be
like Mr the the great Mr ravish shastri
there's no need to comment give a live
running commentary about everything okay
keep quiet there's no need to speak
about everything and and voice your
opinion about everything so yeah that's
where we
are um abishek Kumar says what are the
chances of Iran's success as uh it plans
to attack Israel MyUI says Israel is
threatening Iran with War what are my
thoughts yeah
so so Iran says it wants to attack
Israel that's what one hears in the
media the news and Israel is threatening
Iran with war so what has happened let's
let's try and unpack what has happened
so there's this guy the the chief of
Hamas who was living in in Qatar right
uh what's his name Han so this guy the
chief of Hamas the most powerful leader
the most prominent and Powerful leader
of
Hamas uh he goes to Iran he goes to tan
to attend this wearing in ceremony or
inauguration ceremony of the new Iranian
uh president because the previous
Iranian president unfortunately died in
an aircraft crash helicopter crash so
there's a new president being
inaugurated and this guy the Hamas Chief
goes to tan to attend this to to
participate in the ceremony in that
event now Hamas uh they operate out of
uh Palestine okay Palestine I mean Gaza
Etc Gaza mainly
Gaza the West
Bank
um the Gaza Strip
essentially not the West Bank the Gaza
Strip so uh they operate out of this and
they are known to be an Iranian proxy
Iran also has proxies in Syria in Iraq
Etc Iran is a very geopolitically
ambitious Nation it uh it punches way
above its weight it has power projection
capabilities and it uses those power
projection capabilities in the
region so uh Hamas is an Iranian proxy
now is and and Hamas is classified as a
terrorist organization and it does
of course conduct terrorist activities
so it's a terrorist organization and
it's a proxy of
Iran now so so lots of people will say
that that makes Iran the bad guy right
but there are many other nations that
have used terrorist proxies to to
further their agenda for example the
United States funded and financed
Pakistani terrorism in India for decades
1970s 1980s 1990s 2000 all the way up to
the 2000s okay so does that make the US
a terrorist Nation a terrorist regime
one could make make the same argument so
I would say that there is look we have
to be very clear about one thing okay
firstly there is no morality in
geopolitics there is no morality in
geopolitics there's no right or wrong
good or bad in geopolitics every nation
has a set of national interests and
every nation will pursue those national
interests in any way possible that is
simply the rule the way the game is
played and the more powerful you are the
more you can get away with and the US is
the most powerful and that's why they
they able to get away with essentially
everything whatever they want including
supporting Pakistani terrorists against
India and bleeding India for decades so
now Iran is being called a supporter a
state supporter of terrorism okay
whatever and Hamas obviously is a
terrorist organization no doubt about it
so this guy the chief of Hamas goes to
thean and he is assassinated allegedly
uh we have not seen any evidence of the
assassination and the Iranians are
claiming that the Zionist regime has
carried out the assassination which
means Israel so they have alleged that
Israel carried out the assassination in
tan well if that is true that is
humiliating for first of all for Iran
because Israel comes into your capital
city and takes out a guy who a few hours
ago with was with your
president okay in a pinpoint strike that
is humiliating for Iran if that is true
it also proves that Israel's
capabilities are topnotch they can go
and do anything anywhere and it also
sends a message to Israel's enemies that
no matter who you are no matter where
you are no matter who is protecting you
we can come out come and take you out we
can take you out we can take out your
children your grandchildren your entire
family
which is what they did
to
okay so there is that okay that's the
message it sends now this guy uh Han he
was the most powerful leader of Hamas he
was the only guy who could unify the
various Palestinian uh political
factions with him
gone the
Palestinian uh political cause is is now
disunited it is fragmented
and Hamas also doesn't have any leader
who can properly unify Hamas so that has
severely that is going to severely
impact is Iran's power projection
capabilities in the West Bank sorry in
in Gaza okay in the vinity of Israel
which is bad for Iran so that's what's
happening and this guy okay Han among
all the terrorists he was a moderate
terrorist what does it mean it means
that despite being a terrorist he was
he had
expressed a view that he was in favor of
talks with Israel and he would perhaps
be willing to entertain a ceasefire
offer from Israel so from that
perspective he was a moderate of course
he was a terrorist but among all the
terrorists he was the moderat of all the
terrorists okay so now with him gone
what happens is that Hamas is going to
take a completely Hardline stance
complete Hardline stance
they will definitely reject any offer of
negotiations or whatever from Israel if
that ever happens and it this this
alleged assassination of this guy has
also bolstered
netanyahu's political standing in Israel
he has been on very shaky political
ground there are corruption cases
against him if he loses If he if he has
to step down as the leader of Israel he
may go to jail okay and so on so he is
on Shaky Ground and this you know it it
elevates his political position it makes
his political future more stable and
better so from this strengthened
political position Netanyahu can
actually now offer a ceas fire to Hamas
and he knows that Hamas will reject
it and that can be the pretext for for
taking the war or the conflict to the
next
level so that is all that's happening
right now okay so Israel
it may offer a his fire it may go to war
with Iran Iran has already said that
they will retaliate in some fashion okay
but we have to understand that the the
two Nations they are about a, kilometers
apart let's let's try and measure
measure the distance roughly yeah about
900 kilometers roughly 1,000 kilometers
in distance in a straight line and how
does Iran fight Israel from the distance
how does Iran do that they could launch
another drone strike a few hundred
drones like last time but the last drone
strike was mostly ineffective it me many
of the drones were shot down and those
that did indeed hit their targets did
not make did not cause any significant
damage they did not take out any high
value targets so overall it was kind of
a failure yeah well what about doing
that again well that will only make them
look even more Toothless the Iranians
they don't have an Air Force that's
capable of bridging you know flying that
th000 kilom distance taking out targets
and coming back so what does Iran
do they don't have too many options they
will have to use proxies and fight and
and and uh you know engage their enemy
at a time in a place of their choosing
that's what they would have to
do um and Israel can certainly launch
air strikes against Iran they have good
they have a very powerful Air Force and
they do that they will have to overfly
Iraq Etc if they do this but yeah the
the Israelis are certainly capable of
doing that and then obviously there's
the nuclear Factor Israel is a non-
declared Undeclared nuclear power they
beli to have about 80 or so maybe 100
nuclear warheads by now Iran possibly
could also have become a nuclear power
they may already have I would imagine
sufficient nuclear faile material for
maybe 5 10 nuclear war
possible so there's also a nuclear
Dimension here so there's so much
happening and this is a situation that's
fluid it's a situation that's in in
progress uh one can just hope that it
doesn't devolve into an actual War I
mean first of all how do you fight a war
from a th000 kilometers apart that
that's the first logistical problem um
so it will be a long-term longdistance
War if it does happen but yeah the
Iranians do have proxies among uh in
Syria in
Gaza in Yemen as well so they could they
could cause a lot of problems for Israel
the US Etc and this could lead
to a certain rise in global oil prices
Etc which would not be good for anybody
now what about India what should our
position be in this see we Indians are
tremendously emotional and we believe
that wherever there's a conflict we have
to take a side we have to take this side
or that side we have to take a
side why do we have to take a side from
our perspective Iran and Israel are both
reasonably friendly
Nations neither nation has any special
love for India okay despite whatever you
may believe Indians are so unrealistic
and so emotional neither of these
nations Iran and Israel has any special
love for India but both are reasonably
friendly towards
India so we don't need to take any signs
we should simply urge both Nations to
calm down
and you know resolve your differences
over a negotiating over the negotiating
table in negotiations through diplomacy
don't fight that's what we should say we
don't need to take
sides so yeah that's that's uh my
perspective on
this Luna live says what's your opinion
on the student protest in Bangladesh
this is an American regime change
operation okay that's what it
is that's what's What's Happening Here
the Americans they have the
ability to
to they have this ability in India as
well as we've seen okay and they have
done this in Thailand as well and many
countries to carry out these uh color
revolutions regime change operations and
shik Hina the leader of Bangladesh the
prime minister is very Pro India and she
has made the astonishing allegation
multiple times this year that the
Americans
have they they want to carve
out uh Christian Nation okay let's go to
the map they want to carve out a
Christian Nation out of Bangladesh India
and
Burma so parts of Bangladesh parts of
Burma and parts of India which is
mizoram and Manipur especially Manipur
will be part of a new Christian
Nation and they wanted shikina to agree
to this and she has not agreed that's
why they are doing all this and they
also want the Americans also want an
island okay this island
here uh what is it
called I wonder what it's called but
they they want St Martin's Island they
want to construct an Air Force and Naval
Base here from which they can project
power over
India and obviously in other parts of
this region as well so fasina has not
agreed to this and that's why the
Americans are after her and these
student protests are nothing but that
okay they are part of the American
pressure
tactics and it's very easy to mislead
students very easy especially when their
professors are on the US payroll okay
and they get all these junkets Etc to go
to the west and give business class
tickets and and five star hotel stays
and you know give a lecture somewhere
and everybody treats you very well so
obviously you'll be Pro us so it's very
easy for the Americans to to harness
student power in any Nation they've done
this in various parts of the world
they've done it in India they've done it
in Thailand in 2020 21 they're doing it
Bangladesh now so it is an attempt to
change the regime in Bangladesh the
Americans want the the opposition to
come to power the opposition is strongly
strongly
anti-india okay with ently anti
anti-india and the media is making it
look like the students are being
oppressed by the government of
Bangladesh which is
nonsense so India must stand with
shikina she is a strongly pro-india
leader one of the one of the few
pro-india leaders in the Indian
subcontinent and the Americans don't
like this so what the Americans want to
do is they want to create a new Pakistan
east of India a new Pakistan a Christian
Pakistan we have we already have one
Pakistan to our West okay and that
nation has cut off our historical access
to Eurasia we can no longer connect with
Eurasia by road because
Pakistan has cut off our access and so
has China and now what the Americans
will do they will create a new
artificial Christian Nation a new
Pakistan in in the east of India in
India's Far East which will cut off our
access to Southeast Asia so India will
be completely cut off off by land with
the rest of the world we will have to go
either by air or by sea and who controls
the air who controls the sea it's the
Americans that's what the Americans want
to do and that is why Manipur is burning
okay so all of this what's happening in
Manipur what's happening in Bangladesh
the Civil War that's raging in Burma
right now all of this has a geopolitical
dimension these are not uh these are all
correlated okay that's what's happening
so I hope the government of India
will
withstand this pressure and so will
Bangladesh when we need to support
Bangladesh in this
matter
okay zixer it says taxes like America
but services like Somalia so what are my
thoughts
well I'm I'm afraid you're
right I'm afraid you're right we have an
extremely uh convoluted tax
regime multiple layers of Taxation very
high very heavy
taxation which is fine as long as you
get the services you're paying for but
you don't get the services you're paying
for for example in the US you have to
pay I don't know 30 40% tax depending on
your income level Etc but you get
Services the government provides
services they provide you excellent
Transportation excellent roads Law and
Order and everything right it's a first
world
country uh in India you get tax the same
kind of tax but what services do you get
you get nothing then the people who pay
the most taxes they they suffer the most
unfortunately that's that's true so look
uh tax is obviously is necessary the
government needs taxation Revenue in
order to run the country but my point is
make it as simple as
possible you know what lots of
bureaucrats lots of not all but lots of
bureaucrats and lots of media people and
lots of politicians what they claim they
claim that only 2% or 3% of Indians pay
tax which is an outright
lie okay because every single Indian
pays taxes if you if you
buy one kilo of potatoes you're paying
tax on that it's already been taxed
whether you buy a a chai a glass of chai
that even that there is tax in that you
you paid 10 Rupees for that they like
like three rupees or four rupees of that
is tax the government takes a cut of
every single monetary transaction that
happens in this country everything is
taxed there is GST on
everything so you are already paying
taxes but those of you who pay income
tax first of all you'll pay 20 30
whatever per income tax so out of every
1,000 rupees you earn you come home with
700 bucks let's say 700 rupees then you
have to pay Road tax then you have to
every time you buy something you to pay
tax on that if you purchase a house you
to pay stamp Duty and registration Duty
and whatnot so you tax your money has
already been taxed and now you have to
pay tax on top of that and then tax on
top of that it is horrible so why can't
we just have a simplified tax regime
where you simply pay tax on every time
you purchase something do do with income
tax make everything GST or make it just
simple right why do you have to make it
so
complicated and please provide services
obviously it's it's not it's easier said
than done it's not this government
that's responsible for the condition the
state that India is in they're trying
their best to improve it no doubt about
that and much more can be done no doubt
about that
either
uh so that's where we are it's it's not
an enviable position to be in if you are
the government of India you do need
taxation you can make it easier if you
want to but you're not doing it but then
tax is anyway going to be there and then
people will obviously not be happy
especially the middle class Etc who are
the ones who are paying income tax they
won't be happy about this and they will
voice their unhappiness and then the
government has to swallow that pain of
course it's just they can choose to
ignore it if they
want uh so yeah what we need to do is
the we need to make services in India
better and there are countries with the
same kind of you know per capita GDP as
India that provide much better
services so that unfortunately is is per
the purview the domain of the state
governments in India and many state
governments have certain problems
allegedly so yeah that's where we are we
need to overall as a nation raise our
standards and it's not a to it's not a
bottom up process it's a top- down
process but we are told it's a bottom of
process and that's why we blame
ourselves for everything that's wrong
with with India the Indian citizen is is
made to self flagellate that everything
that's bad in India is my fault it is
the fault of the people of India what
what do they say pra tar Raja no that's
not how it is Raja T pra that's that's
how it should be but
yeah
okay um Daran Singh says why should we
work hard if you're all going to die one
day how am I even relevant in this 8
billion population world how will my
work how is it going to be relevant in
the upcoming years life seems
meaningless
look no one has an answer to what's the
purpose of life what's the meaning of
life what is all this about of course
everyone's going to
die every single human being who has
existed on this planet has died so that
is the Fate
that awaits all of us so then the
question is then the the fact is the
reality is that the moment you're born
the clock is ticking and you are heading
in that direction right and you don't
know how much time you have only the
gods know that okay guess so you have a
certain limited amount of time and then
what you have to decide is what you do
what are you going to do with this
time you can while away your time doing
nothing playing games scrolling social
media or you can take extremely heavy
challenges which will make your life
uncomfortable what do you do but
whatever you do you you're going to die
and most likely in a few years nobody is
going to remember you nobody's going to
remember me do you remember who your
great great grandfather grandmother was
do you remember the name you don't
remember them so what's the point of
this what's the point of all of this is
the
question my answer is
the meaning of life is whatever you want
it to be the purpose of life is whatever
you want it to be if you want if you
feel that life is meaningless and
there's no purpose then it's going to be
like that for you but if someone else
decides that my life is going to have
this purpose and my actions will have
this meaning I'm doing it for this
meaning this reason yes I'm going to die
maybe nobody will remember me in a few
years but so what at least I
will live a meaningful life from my
perspective so it's entirely up to you
you are the architect of your life you
are the main character in your story who
cares what others think at least you
going to have a good time right so my
point
is don't worry about what
others think about you or will think of
you in the
future you are the main character people
will come and go but you going to be
with you with yourself forever as long
as this life exists maybe who knows
beyond that also perhaps so stop
worrying worrying about
others think of what you want to do ask
yourself who are you as a person what
are your likes dislikes what are what is
it that gives you give gives your life
meaning and then you pursue that and
don't worry about what other people
think of you and what they will think
about you after you gone and all that
so essentially life is what you make of
it the purpose of life is whatever you
want it to be the meaning of life is
also whatever you want it to be so my
point my my simple thing is make your
life the greatest life possible make it
an adventure be the real main character
of your life don't be what what do they
say NPC right don't be an NP NPC be your
main character live your life as as
Grand as you can make it be make make it
make it to
be
okay stofile says are Michael Phelps
usan bolt and Simon biles the greatest
athletes of all time as no one has ever
come close to their to the skills that
they have and who's winning gold for
India I think there are okay so Michael
Phelps usen bold Simon BS they
definitely are great art athletes but
there have been others too and probably
people don't remember those today so let
me give you a few examples of great
athletes uh let us go to Google and let
me uh okay how about
Alexander
kelin this guy Alexander
carelin the greatest wrestler in human
history in his entire professional
career he lost one fight which which
happened to be his last fight
okay and that to he lost on on a stupid
technicality and this guy was just
unbelievable incredible nobody could
defeat him he was a super heavyweight
and he used to pick up other guys as if
they were nothing look at
that he's picking up a guy who's like
120 130 kilos like a toy and tossing him
so Alexander Karin is the greatest
wrestler of all time nobody comes close
to him and he's now a politician
successful politician okay that's one
then you obviously have Mike
Tyson great great probably the greatest
boxer of all time some people will say
it's Muhammad Ali some people will say
somebody else but among those who I have
seen he's the greatest and uh
devastating power this guy tremendous
okay so yeah this guy tremendous and
obviously uh Yan Bolt
definitely the greatest Sprinter of all
time Simone biles gymnast I believe yes
gymnast uh yeah she's good Michael
Phelps uh that guy
torp torpedo that guy also was good the
Australian uh great swimmers probably
Michael Phelps is the greatest and so on
so yeah there are many of these athletes
who are the greatest of their time
really admirable people and there's a
lot you can learn from them uh the kind
of discipline they they have uh
exhibited the single-minded focus that
they had in the pursuit of gold and
glory for themselves and for Country Etc
it's a lot you can learn from
them okay now the next question is who's
winning gold for India uh I hope we win
a few Golds this time the Olympics um
not sure how many we will win I hope
there's at least one who's the guy the
Javin throw guy I forget his name man um
the guy who won Gold last time
tremendous tremendous
athlete um I I I hope he
wins so yeah I hope somebody wins gold
for
India uh Ki says do you know Telugu no
I'm I'm I'm afraid I don't know
Telugu very interesting language I I
know people who know T we all know
people who know but I
myself uh don't quite know
the
okay uh goam gambir hello
Coach says how do you how do you see
Insurgency issue in the Northeast
particularly nagaland please shed some
light on the way forward and if there's
any solution soon I'm sorry if this
wasn't a good time to ask this question
no it's
okay um look the Insurgency issue in the
Far East of India the Northeast like we
say has been around for a very long time
okay it's not something that's happening
right now so let's once again go to the
map I have to explain where this region
is the Far East of India which everybody
calls the
Northeast the Far East of India is these
states over here from arunachal Pradesh
all the way down to uh
mizoram and from the time India became
independent from the British 1950s
onwards the these states all of these
states had multiple
insurgencies okay and uh apart from
arunachal prades Mostly but you had
multiple insurgencies and and Insurgent
groups in nagaland in mizoram in Manipur
and Assam Etc and in mizoram the
situation became so bad that in 1966 I
believe the prime minister of India
Indira Gandhi had to launch air strikes
on
separatists now these separatists were
funded and financed by foreign powers it
is known it is known that the CIA was
funding various terrorist Insurgent
groups in certain states in the Far East
of India it is also known that the
Chinese were funding and
aiding such separatists since the 1950s
1960s onwards even the CIA uh Pakistan
was involved Pakistan is a US proxy
obviously and so on at the time there
was East Pakistan which is now
Bangladesh so there was a lot happening
there as well so uh yeah it's it's been
around for a very long time okay you had
ASA the Armed Forces special Powers Act
which was in force in Manipur and other
parts of the Far East from the 1950s
onwards 1958 onwards for decades it was
in place imagine that how horrible it
must have been for the
people for the civilians over there so
it was it's been a disaster it's been an
absolute disaster and the
what exacerbated the situation is the
nean regime's decision to christianize
the entire Northeast they uh banned any
Hindu religious people from from
entering the Far East of India and they
gave complete C blanch to American
missionaries to
christianize very large parts of of the
Far East of India so almost the whole of
nagaland is now Christian the entirety
of mizoram is Christian there
is the situation in other parts of the
far east as well and that has
contributed
to uh the situation that we see right
now because uh essentially it's a church
that rules very large parts of this
region uh so what's the way forward the
way forward is India needs to strengthen
itself India needs to get become more
powerful so that we can push back
against foreign interference in the
region um as we we know there is the
situation that's happening in Manipur
right now Manipur has been a flame since
uh May last year cookie terrorists
cookie separatists have been causing
Mayhem they are uh foreign infiltrators
in this region in in India Millions I
would not say Millions but lacks of them
have infiltrated into Manipur in the
past few years because of the open
borders that have been in place and the
situation is is is dire right now the
Americans want to create an artificial
Nation artificial Christian Nation
Cookie Land Cookie Land for Christ in
this region to cut off India's access
from Southeast Asia so that's a
situation and I don't see any immediate
solution to this it's going to get bad
before it's going to get worse before it
gets
better so yeah that's where we
are the greatest sin in geopolitics is
weakness and right now India is not
powerful enough and don't blame Mr Modi
for that okay Mr Modi didn't make the
the India that he has inherited wasn't
made by him he's trying to do his best
I'm sure he can do better I'm not saying
he can't but it's not the situation is
not of his
making okay Manipur for example it's not
the BJP the the the Modi government's
fault that this has
happened they could have obviously done
things differently
they should have been aware of the large
scale industrial scale IM illegal
immigration happening into
Manipur uh certain things can still be
done differently especially when it
comes to well I don't I'll not go into
that but things can be done
differently but overall the situation
was not created by this government they
simply inherited a very bad situation
now it's going to take at least 20 years
and what's the solution minimum 20 the
solution is to expel all foreigners out
of India it's as simple as that many of
them have been they claim that they have
been here forever and they have AAR
cards and passports and whatnot what do
you do now what do you do now well the
government has to find a solution you
cannot absorb them all every goddamn
Foreigner comes into India and becomes
an Indian millions of bangladeshis
millions of cookies millions of God
knows who who else everybody and none of
them has any allegiance to Indian
culture and civilization that's what we
are doing it's high time we stop that
but it's going to take
time
okay um T Chandra says a lot of Afghan
pashun believe that they are Ben Israel
a part of one of the 12 tribes from
Judea are the Jews and the pashon
genetically
Brothers genetically there's nothing in
common between the Jews and the pashun
absolutely nothing but the uh pashun
have been brainwashed in the past 1,000
years roughly into believing that they
are descendants of one of the Lost
tribes of Israel and so they believe it
and that that's what what their
ancestors have been telling them for the
past I don't know few
Generations so they all believe it today
it's it's something they see as
self-evident so yeah most pasun believe
that they are descendants of an Israeli
tribe and they have nothing to do with
the subcontinent we are descendants of
foreign conquerors
that's what they believe well what can I
do about
it
okay okay Alan J wictor says who does
Israel serve you have said in the past
that Sovereign countries are India
America China and Russia and to some
extent France then which country
controls Iran good question so
sovereignty is something that that very
few Nations genuinely have um when so no
nation is entirely immune from external
interference in its Internal Affairs
even the US is not immune from that but
among all the powers in the n in the
world there's only four nations like I
have said the the US Russia China and
India that and these four essentially
that are genuinely Sovereign Nations
France well it's part of NATO it's part
of the EU so there are sovereignty
issues there now the question is a very
good question about Iran what about Iran
how Sovereign or to what extent is Iran
Sovereign so we talking about this
nation next to India I mean there's a
temporary nation in in between the two
but yeah Iran our historical neighbor so
Iran you see Iran isn't controlled by
Any Other Nation India Iran doesn't have
any foreign military bases on its
territory so from that perspective it is
reasonable
Sovereign but it is it has been
suffering from us sanctions for a very
long time brutal devastating sanctions
on Iran because of which it has had to
become let's say so to say an ally of
China as well as
Russia and that's why it is
significantly influenced by those two
Nations China as well as Russia so today
people speak about this access the China
Russia Iran
Access North Korea is also spoken of in
this in the same breath uh and Syria as
well so Iran is part of that axis and
uh so it cannot entirely go against the
wishes and desires of Russia and China
it has to kind of exceed to those and
because of that constraint you can say
that you can possibly say that Iran
isn't entirely Sovereign even though it
doesn't have foreign military bases on
its on its
territory uh so it doesn't serve as such
any Nations any other nations but it has
to stay to to keep China and Russia
happy and it has to keep them in good
humor and obviously for that you have to
sometimes give certain concessions uh
privately that nobody may come to know
about but for example you will give the
Chinese of 25e strategic Alliance de
and you will sell tremendous amounts of
oil to the Chinese at discounted rates
and in exchange the Chinese will invest
some money $400 billion something into
your economy over a 25 year period that
sort of thing quid proo that sort of
thing but you to keep the Chinese happy
you also have to keep the Russians happy
so these
constraints uh they prevent you from
acting the way you otherwise would have
wanted to act so that is the situation
that Iran is
in uh Samar acharia says why do roads
get damaged in the rainy season
Southeast Asian countries are also
tropical countries but their roads are
way better than
ours um let's talk look you know what
what is one of the major problems that
India faces one of India's major
problems probably India's core problem
Central problem is corruption
okay and that's why roads get damaged
every year during monsoons in the rainy
season there is no reason for a
road to get po hold and damaged every 12
months there's no reason for it it
happens when the significant portion of
the budget allocated for the road is
misappropriated and inferior grade
materials are used to construct the road
deliberately
so that next time next year when it
reins again it's going to get damaged so
you're going to have to again allocate a
large sum of money to repair the road
and once again you're going to
misappropriate most of it and again
construct a substandard road which means
next year again you're going to have to
repeat the process so it's a recurring
process and whoever is involved in this
makes money year after year after
year okay I'm not talking about any
specific city or state or location in
India I'm just saying hypothetically in
any in various parts of India this may
be happening okay and that's why roads
get damaged during the rainy
season if you remove the corruption
factor
from from India then India will be a way
different way better country but that's
where we are today in India India
essentially runs on corruption and my
question is where is India's war on
corruption when is it going to happen
right okay once again this question is
Iran going to take a huge action in
response to the death of Hamas leader if
yes what could it be then let's let's
once again analyze it what options does
does Iran have look at the geography the
map tells you half the story the
distance between Iran's borders in
Israel's borders is about 900 or th000
kilometers roughly 1,000 kilometers so
if Iran wants to take a huge action what
will it do will it launch drone strikes
like a few hundred drones it did that
last time a few months ago that was kind
of an exercise in fertility most of the
drones were shot down and those that did
land in Israel and hit some targets they
did not cause any significant damage or
take out any high value targets so
overall it was an exercise in futility
so let's say they do it again once again
it won't have much of an effect which
will make them appear too
less so that's one option which may not
really work the other option is can they
launch missile strikes well missile
strikes Also may not be that effective
because the Israelis have this iron
drone Dome system which is pretty
effective so once again that may also
not work Iran doesn't have the Air Force
Power to launch a strike an air strike
on Israel so that also doesn't work so
what options does does Iran have is the
question the only thing Iran can do is
to launch Terror attacks on Israel
through proxies like Hamas like hisbah
like the huis in the ET SE Etc that's
all Iran can do what else can it do it
doesn't have the ability to launch a
large scale attack on on Israel even if
it wants to so it's going to have to do
do it through proxy
methods okay that's what could happen
okay
um um mcloven says what's with the hate
towards India recently every second
tweet is about India you said it was
coming but I didn't expect it at this
level I'll tell you what's happening
Indians are becoming increasingly
relevant politically in the US and in
the west especially the US so in the
past who did you who did you have uh you
had Nikki Haley you had Bobby Jindal
peush Jindal who are who had to convert
to Christianity and and and acquire
foreign names in order to you know be
relevant politically but
today you have people like VI
ramaswami and many more upcoming people
who are unabashedly Indian they are
unabashedly Hindu they don't see
they don't see the need to convert to
Christianity to be relevant in the US
they don't see the need to change their
names to be relevant in the US and they
are tremendously competent VI ramaswami
can take on anybody and Destroy any
debater and this is just the beginning
Indians are coming up in the US okay and
Indians are better than the than the
average American because the Americans
have ensured they took the best of the
Indians
right so what we are seeing is that the
Indians are now threatening to take over
the US not just uh earlier it was just
businesses right motels
711s and uh Indians would be doctors
Indian Indians would be lawyers ET they
would give Services they would provide
services and keep a low profile but now
it's no longer the case Indians
are they they're going to take over and
this is visible now and it's just the
beginning in a few years you'll have way
more Indians all over the place all over
the place and Indians are Brash
outspoken not like the Asians they're
not like the Chinese and Eastern Asians
who keep quiet and are reserved now
Indians are like loud and they're going
to go and take whatever they can and
they're
competent and they're better than the
average American so the Americans are
now feeling this you know they're
feeling a threat
they're feeling threatened by the rise
of the Indians the brown people in the
US and that's why there is this
tremendous outpouring of hatred towards
India and racism towards Indians that is
what's happening and towards Hinduism
also Hindu phobia you seeing all that
it's simp simply a symptom it's it's a
reaction a negative reaction to the uh
assertiveness and Rise of all these
assertive Indians in the US and India is
much more visible now there are Indians
are all over social media and Indians
don't you know Indians don't back down
from a fight Indians love arguing and
fighting so you simply can't fight the
Indians you say something bad about
India 300 Indians will come and jump on
you there was this guy recently some
comedian Leonardo ji or something and he
was saying bad things about Indians and
now where is
he so yeah racist person so it's it's
not normal it's natural you Colonial you
colonized people are now threatening to
colonizers how dare you but there's
nothing they can do about it the Indians
are going to take over the
US well they'll try at least so that's
why the that's why you're seeing
this
okay um sidhar Singh Raj purohit says do
you agree that the Middle East will
never attain peace until and unless the
US is a
superpower and how long the US will
remain a superpower despite of its
double turn
policies well one of the characteristics
of a superpower is that they are
hypocritical they have double standards
they say one thing but they do another
thing they will tell everybody to
believe in democracy and freedom and
human rights and they will trample all
over those standards and the more
powerful you are the more you are
entitled to be hypocritical
okay so the most hypocritical nation is
going to be the most powerful Nation you
have to earn the right to be a hypocrite
and the Americans have earned the right
okay so we don't need to get emotional
about this that is simply the way the
world works the world has always had
double
standards the powerful have a set of
rules of their own and the the
powerless they don't get to make the
rules they will just do what what they
said what they're told to do that's just
how the world works
don't feel bad about it don't complain
about it
okay so if a nation has double standards
does it mean that it will no longer be a
superpower
no being a superpower or not being a
superpower has nothing to do with with
having double
standards the US will REM remain a
superpower as long as it knows how to
remain a superpower as long as it
doesn't allow other nations to surpass
it or to threaten it and they and and
they're extremely jealous in this in
this
regard uh they will not allow any
Nation to Aspire to be a great power
then that's what's happening with India
right now uh China is under control by
the US the Chinese economy and the
American economy are deeply intered
intertwined joined at the hip so the
Americans aren't really worried about
China even though they keep on speaking
about China okay you should understand
there's a difference between words and
actions the Americans will keep on
speaking about China keep on hyping up
the Chinese threat the Chinese are not a
threat to the US the Chinese military is
nothing compared to the US military okay
the Chinese are
nowhere
nowhere comparable to the US the
Americans are way more powerful than
China the one nation the
Americans are genuinely worried about
and scared of
is Russia but they will not speak about
it all right um so the Americans are
worried about Russia and that's why
they're trying to encircle Russia and so
on so forth so the US will remain a
superpower as long as they play the game
right as the as long as they play the
game and win
it um but yes the Middle East will never
have peace as long as the Americans are
meddling there that's not going to
happen you're right
parak Johan says do you think the
Olympics is just a competition between
genetic
freaks as in the case of Phelps Michael
Phelps his body produces half the lactic
acid than a normal human being does and
many other things in many other players
you are right actually in in some cases
at
least uh you need to be genetically
genuinely gifted and you need to put in
a tremendous amount of hard work to
succeed at the Olympics
today the Olympics it's no longer you
know the Olympics was originally
supposed to be a competition between
gifted
amateurs it was supposed to be a
compartition between gifted amateurs but
now it's like fully
professional you have to be genetically
gifted the one% of the 1% and you need
to put in a tremendous amount of hard
work and maybe more than a little more
than hard work perhaps some help from
the doctor perhaps so yeah that's what
it is that's what the Olympics is
and that's why nations with larger
populations typically do better in the
Olympics because they have a larger pool
genetic pool to draw from except for
Nations like India in which in in our
case the government simply doesn't care
about India's national Prestige so there
is very little investment in
sports okay
um DK says America is America
deliberately instilling fear about China
in the world they did the same about
many Arab countries the Americans will
play all these games look um like I said
just a while ago uh the Americans keep
on hyping up the alleged China threat
when the real Nation the nation that
they're really worried about is
Russia um and of course they do spare no
effort in demonizing Russia as well so
they do that the Americans are masters
of propaganda their entire media is a
propaganda machine okay and so they will
do it they will do whatever it takes for
them to remain in Pole Position globally
the sole
superpower Sujin says is India an
artificial Nation to counterbalance
China for the us just like an artificial
Nation like Pakistan to counterbalance
India my dear sir India is not an
artificial Nation India is the world's
oldest
civilization we have
always been where we
are here's the map of India okay the
Indian subcontinent was the people who
inhabit the subcontinent we have been
here for 60 70,000 Years 880,000 Years
perhaps we are the oldest civilization
we are the oldest culture that is known
in the world the old oldest known
civilization how can you imagine that we
are an artificial Nation yes in 1940 in
1950 we were redefined as a a nation
state but what we actually are is a
civilization
state so there's nothing artificial
about India India is one of the few
natural uh Nations and and civilizations
in the world the US is an artificial
Nation okay okay it was created recently
through conquest of lands that did not
belong to the Europeans the US is an
artificial Nation so is Canada and so on
so is obviously uh
Pakistan Pakistan is also a temporary
Nation apart from being an artificial
Nation okay okay aush Raj says why is
China pushing suddenly for normal
relations with India we recently had
Commander level meeting in Delhi the
Chinese Ambassador writing peace in the
Hindu Global times praising
India yeah so something is happening for
sure okay uh the Chinese are adopting a
conciliatory approach towards India the
Ambassador is certainly throwing out
this charm offensive the global times is
no
longer you know raising temperatures
shrilly against India it's uh so some
something is is in the work something is
going on we're not quite sure what it is
it looks like the Indian government may
be amenable to allowing Chinese
companies to invest in India and set up
manufacturing plants in India which
would be great for the Chinese economy
because they are facing all kinds of
problems Vis A the west and the Chinese
economy isn't doing great so if the
Chinese get access to this giant market
of India that will be great for their
economy so that's good for them and it's
also good for India if we get Chinese
investment and all that so it looks like
you know it it maybe possible that the
Chinese have realized that there's that
they they stand to lose more than the
gain in a conflict with India because if
need be India can bring in the US
and the West if need be and that will
not be great for China and it's even if
India is standing on its own it will be
difficult for the Chinese to defeat
India the war but a war may still happen
but sometime in the future perhaps maybe
we we are postponing the war by five or
10 years perhaps so overall it looks
like for the time being it may be in
both Nations interests to cooperate for
some time perhaps yeah so that could be
what's in the offing I'm not sure if
it's going to work out that way so we'll
keep an eye on that but right now that's
the direction in which this relationship
seems to be going maybe it's too early
to
say anything concrete or specific about
this but it looks like we may be heading
in that direction but overall please
remember the Chinese are not our friends
as long as the Chinese occupy Tibet we
will never have lasting peace with China
okay uh that is something we should
never forget but yes uh we can certainly
you can you can cooperate with everybody
including your
adversaries that's uh how the game is
played I mean look at Indian politics
learn from your domestic politics I one
day so and so politician is in that
Coalition 12 months later he's in this
Coalition 20 years ago he had
backstabbed these people I'm talking
about some hypothetical politics not
anybody in real but that's typically how
politics has played in India right so
why is it surprising if it if the same
thing happens on a global scale in
geopolitics the same patterns and
principles apply everywhere
tanay Chandra says recently Turkish
media Outlets alleged that Indian row
agents alongside mad was responsible for
the death of is KH the head of
Hamas so what are my views on erdogan
and
turkey these days everybody is going
after India right the Americans first
the Canadians claimed that we tried to
assassinate some second rate
has been terrorist sheltered by by
Canada uh what njar or something then
the Americans alleged that Indian Ro
agents were trying to assassinate uh
terrorists the Americans are
Sheltering and now the Turks apparently
are claiming claiming that India is
involved in the assass in the assass
assassination of the Palestinian
terrorist Han what's going on well my
point is show us the
evidence the evidence are you able to
produce evidence incontrovertible
evidence to substantiate your
allegations none of them can the
Americans haven't provided any evidence
the Canadians under Mr tudo haven't been
able to provide any evidence and over
here Turks well show us the evidence
right I don't think India is into all
these things I don't think India is
doing this uh
that's what I can tell you what are my
views on erdogan and turkey erogan and
turkey
look I would like good relations with
everybody I would like good relations
between India and turkey as well turkey
is a beautiful country no doubt and
interesting history and culture no doubt
interesting population no doubt Mr ER
erdogan interesting guy used to play
football and now
he's the leader in Turkey interesting
guy so what can I say overall I would
like good relations with everybody we
should be everybody's friend but it's
not practically possible in the
world all
right
uh turkey turkey h n
turkey okay let's see what else do we
have uh
uh shat says how can we understand and
visualize spaces with fractional
Dimensions such as 1.5 or 2.5 Dimensions
we can't you can't visualize that it's a
just a mathematical abstraction but it
may be the true reality of the world
maybe the world is e dimensional like uh
like
so Dr subash kak Who is an Indian
American uh
scientist he has proposed this new
Theory
that um that the world is actually e
dimensional 2 point whatever right it's
it's a fractal Dimension it's not
threedimensional four dimensional
whatever it's it's e
dimensional so look there's no way we
can actually visualize it because our
eyes our senses they don't show us the
reality of the world they show us a
simplification of what the world is
light and colors it's all vibrations
it's all
it's it's all photons right photons what
are photons these are wave
packets with frequencies frequencies and
and wavelengths Etc so my point is the
world is way weirder than what we
perceive it to be and it's not possible
for us humans simple animals to to
visualize fractionally dimensional
spaces or even four dimensional five
dimensional space the only thing you can
visualize is threedimensional space or
two dimensional or onedimensional so we
can visualize a sheet of paper which is
a two-dimensional object we can
visualize a string a thread which is
essentially more or less a
one-dimensional object we can even
visualize zero dimensional objects with
just points but we can't visualize
anything beyond three dimensions if you
ask me to visualize a four-dimensional
object I can kind of try to imagine that
but you can't really grasp that so it's
not possible you can't you simply can't
it's simply
a mathematical abstraction it's
something you can use mathematically in
your equations and all but it's very Ely
impossible to visualize
that
okay Anita says I wonder how you managed
to stay away amidst all the geopolitical
turmoil geopolitics is so chaotic um
this decade is a decade of tremendous
change uh you're gonna see change that
is the kind of change you typically see
in multiple decades in this one decade
so yeah things will move really fast
they are moving really fast in the 2020s
so I go away for a couple of weeks three
weeks and so much has changed so much
has happened Trump almost gets killed
yeah and uh the Iran Israel situation
again erupts into into chaos and and a
whole lot is happening there's stuff
happening in Africa as well well Wagner
is involved in so much
so yeah it's it's you got to stay in in
touch with what's happening all the
time okay High pill 91 says why do you
say that if India's GDP grows at 7 or 8%
for 30 Years it'll leave China behind
Haven you seen how aggressively China is
working on technology defense Etc
whatnot and they even claim to beat the
US in all sectors by 2034 forget India
China will defeat even the aliens by
2034 China will defeat the the the
kingdom of alpha centor Proxima centor
by 2040 they will defeat everybody look
everybody can make Grand
claims but what you have to see is
numbers
okay they are working on what some
some an artificial sun kind of thing
they are working on various technology
that nobody has heard of they are claim
GES we have to see evidence of that and
what you me what you have to base your
your your understanding of the world on
the basis has to be something you can
measure not something you to you can
only speculate about so the only things
you can measure are numbers what numbers
GDP Etc we can see that the Chinese GDP
growth is
Contracting everybody can see that the
Chinese economy is no doing well and
there are other problems in China the
total fertility rate has collapsed
there's a demographic disaster that's
coming up so they can invest as much as
they want in technology and all that
they can work on artificial intelligence
and Robotics Etc but nothing can replace
human
beings so my point is you can be swayed
by all the propaganda Etc but I am a
realist I I I stay grounded and I still
say that if India grows at 7 8 9 10 %
for 30 years we will become the second
largest economy in the world soon
enough by 2100 we will we will even
outpace the
us but it's a big big big butt you got
to do it and that's not easy given the
State of Affairs in India the
bureaucracy and the inertia and the
corruption and the divisions in the
country and the pathetic education
system it's hard to it will be very hard
Anisha says you had promised that you
will make a separate video for the dash
rajna War battle of 10 Kings it's been
two years now please make a video on it
if possible okay okay well thank you for
the
reminder and yeah okay I'll put that on
my to-do list Battle of 10
Kings uh what
else Priya
says uh what's your take on men wearing
sari on word magazine do you think it's
okay or it's wokeism and can you please
explain valkism and if it's bad then
why
um look if somebody wants to wear a sar
if a guy wants to wear a sar this is a
free country do whatever you want I
don't care I personally don't
care if if if somebody wants to do it
because they feel the urge to do it they
want to try something different or they
feel that I am not a guy I'm a girl and
I have this feminine Instinct you do it
do it by all means do it it doesn't
offend me I don't care
my my issue is when you try
to do this to influence people and to
try to change people's minds
okay I have for example let's talk about
religious conversions if somebody
decides that from tomorrow I want to
convert to so and so religion because I
feel an affinity to towards that and by
all means do it by all means do it I
have absolutely nothing against that but
when people
try to convert people to a specific
religion on an industrial scale by
giving inducements of money and by
trying to influence people's minds
especially um gullible people then
that's a problem okay because that is an
attempt at demographic
re-engineering similarly when you're
trying when you are trying to spread
certain
ideologies symbolically by putting
certain images on magazines on the front
page of magazines you're doing it for a
nefarious
purpose then I have a problem with that
so my point is I am
absolutely I have absolutely nothing
against gay people I have absolutely
nothing against people who want to wear
whatever they want I have absolutely
nothing nothing against Anybody
Everybody should be free to do whatever
they want to do as long as it is legal
that's what I believe but when you're
trying to influence the minds of
youngsters of young people of
children
that's what I am against that that is
something wrong and this is and that is
something that's coming from outside of
this country that is essentially an
attempt by external forces to influence
the minds and hearts of children
children and youngsters in
India why am I saying it's foreign
forces because this has never been part
of Indian
culture men wearing
saris okay and if someone's wearing
wearing a sar there that's fine but why
do you need to put it up on magazines
and multiple magazines there is
definitely um a campaign that is going
on to promote certain ideologies and
that's the V ideology that we're talking
about what is VM is the second question
what is bism well wokeism essentially is
an assault against culture it's an
assault against the family system it's
an assault against Traditional
Values and and some people will say
what's wrong what's wrong with changing
your values in your systems and all
what's so great about Traditional Values
well Traditional Values have worked for
thousands of years you see it it it it
gives you a stable Society it gives you
stable productive Society
whichever Society you're talking about
whichever culture you're talking about
whether it's the west east whatever
every region has its own specific set of
cultural norms Etc which have worked for
that
region now if you are made to believe
that your culture is inferior then you
will feel that you need to change it but
then let's do all this stuff so valkism
is all about destroying the family
system you know High rates of divorce
single mothers that sort of things see
exactly what's happening in the US they
want to import import that into
India so in the US so vocalism has come
come out of the US okay it is a
continuation it's it's an evolution a
morphing of the uh Marxist ideology that
has been uh ruling us academic campuses
since the
1960s and it has now morphed into
valkism what we call bism so this
Marxist leftist ideology first co-opted
feminis is M and ruined feminism
feminism it was a good cause it was
necessary in the US it was necessarily
in the west feminism but then Marxism
coopted feminism hijacked feminism and
completely distorted
it and now they they have they started
they have started pushing self
mutilation and and
hormonal disruption of the body and
whatnot and now they're trying in the US
okay now they're trying to export to
Nations like India my point is if you
want to do it it's fine you don't need
to export it to us okay it's not part of
what we do it's not never been part of
our way of life our way of life is
superior to yours you may not believe it
I don't
care uh so that's what it is bism is
about destroying the family system it's
about destroying your culture so that
you can become an atomized society in
which the individual is the unit of
society not the family and when the
individual becomes the unit of society
it means the family system is broken you
no longer value family you are no longer
in contact with your family and then the
corporations and the media can control
you and you become a
consumer and India becomes a market
India should not produce anything India
should just consume consume consume
that's what they want that's the
issue um
okay abishek says what are India's
options now that China has started
trading Pakistan the j31 P fighter jet
f414 jet engines have been delayed by
the US is rd33 better Cav engine is also
making some progress what's your opinion
look we should look we don't have any
indigenous jet engine technology right
now we have the Cav engine that is able
to produce a certain amount of thrust
which is not exactly what we need it is
less than what we need so you can either
pay exor or exorbitant amounts of money
to the French or the Russians and buy
their technology in case they are
willing to give the technology I think
it may happen the Russians and the
French or and SL or the French may give
us the technology eventually at a price
at a very heavy extortion price I think
whatever the price is we should get the
technology because
developing a powerful jet engine takes a
lot of time
okay uh so uh
we don't have too many options right now
Beggars can't be
choosers even the Chinese are are they
are trying to replicate Russian jet
engine technology they are making some
progress in that uh the the Russian
Saturn engine or whatever it was the
Chinese are trying to
replicate the Americans will do will do
their best to arm twist
India and to extract concessions from
India delaying the the uh delivery of uh
jet engines
and so on which will uh impact the tages
fighter program the Chinese will
obviously try to encircle India via
Pakistan by doing whatever they can if
even offering that j31 fighter jet or
whatever training Pakistani pilots and
so on so look these are just the facts
of of of the world okay that's just the
way the world is you can either complain
about it and cry about it or you can do
whatever is possible within your means
so that's what India must do
India needs to buy beg borrow or steal
jet engine technology okay that's it we
need we need
that
alternatively use the existing Cav
engine in fighter planes but use two
engines instead of one so that will give
you enough thrust that's also something
you can do but ideally you want a
powerful enough single jet engine so buy
big Bor steel like you say you know
there's everything's fair in geopolitics
there is no right or wrong in
geopolitics get what your nation needs
get it done somewhere or the other
that's my
opinion AJ 91 says will abolishing
Indian tax be good for the Indian
economy yeah absolutely we already have
the GST we already have that right every
single thing that is bought or sold
there is a tax that the government gets
on it so why do you need to have
multiple layers of Taxation why just
make it's simple right it's not like we
don't want to pay the government tax we
we're giving tax to the government every
time we buy a single item I buy a mouse
I buy a pencil I buy a pen I buy one of
these books or whatever I'm paying tax
to the
government every single monetary
transaction gives a tax to the
government so why do we need income tax
why do we need so many different kinds
of tax why why why just to keep those
baboos employed in the ministry
right come on man make it make life
simple for Indians make life easy for
Indians that's what I would urge the
government of India to
do uh Breezy says I'm 26 I just want
Native Americans to be appreciated I do
appreciate Native Americans they are the
true Natives and I would say the true
well the true citizens of North
America the people who are ruling North
America are descendants descendants of
colonizers descendants of Invaders
occupiers settler colonialism the Native
Americans have been disenfranchised they
have been reduced to second class
citizens in their own land and that is a
travesty that needs to be
rectified and uh yeah I would like to
see better days again for the true
natives of the Americas the Native
Americans for sure
Shri ramachandra namaha says is bat able
to tackle China and the
US look U China is about four times more
powerful than par the US is
about uh 20 20 times more powerful than
parat so from that perspective we are no
match okay so when you are not powerful
when you are weak you have to be more
intelligent and you to play intelligent
games that's what India must
do so you know in geopolitics what you
do is you play one against the other
when there are two enemies who are both
powerful you play one against the other
and make sure they fight and they don't
come and harm you there are lots of such
things you can do you know
s read the arastra there's so many
things you can do Etc so we need
to you know over come a certain amount
of adversity for a certain amount of
time maybe until 2040 2050 and it's
going to be a difficult period of time
for us very difficult period of time for
us but I think we can do it okay so
despite our significant weakness right
now relative to these two Nations we are
on track to become much more powerful in
the future but for that we need
uninterrupted economic growth for a
period of 20 to 30 years minimum and
that must
happen and we also need to ensure there
is no military conflict that we get
embroiled in during this time period so
all that needs to happen for us to reach
where we need to reach which won't be
easy but nothing worthwhile is easy in
life
so um SP Joker says who was Yuko Mishima
and what was his vision for Japan yuk
Mishima was a poet an
author um a
philosopher and bodybuilder martial
artist Etc he was a Japanese
nationalist he was in favor of a
genuinely Sovereign independent Japan
free from us
domination and his vision for Japan was
genuine freedom for Japan eviction of
the Americans from Japan the Americans
have more than 120 permanent us
permanent military bases on Japanese
soil and he obviously did not like that
and he wanted the Japanese uh
self-defense forces to develop some
national pride and uh evate the
Americans from Japan and obviously he
did not get to see his vision come alive
Vision happen because Japan is still
Occupied Japan is still under permanent
use military occupation and Yukio
Mishima ended his life by committing seu
after giving a
speech to the cots of the Japanese
self-defense
forces yes um very interesting person
and I have some of his books somewhere
somewhere Adar says please pick my
question do you think physics and all
disciplines of science are stagnating I
don't think all the disciplines of
science are stating but physics has hit
a brick wall like I've said many times
there's nothing new that's happening in
physics Applied Physics there's lot
that's happening okay but core physics
fundamental physics theoretical physics
we are not making any progress we have
hit a brick wall we slammed into a brick
wall and there's been no
new progress in our understanding of the
universe since roughly
1980 the last big Advance was the uh
the theory of inflation cosmological
inflation that was proposed by Alan gut
what year was that 7879 80 81 somewhere
around that time since then there's been
nothing nothing no new insight
theoretical advance in physics nothing
uh and much of it probably has to do
with this with the kind of system
Academia has become extremely
uh well it promotes group think it
doesn't promote uh thinking out of the
box too much emphasis on various things
and all and the strength Theory Mafia
has taken over the physics departments
in the west and in India there's nothing
happening anyway because the education
system is rotten to the core and no
one's allowed to do any research and
mediocre people are promoted at the
expense of the brilliant ones and so on
so yeah when it comes to physics
complete stagnation when it comes to The
Cutting Edge of physics theoretical
physics uh um other disciplines of
science I'm not sure there is stagnation
as such especially applied sciences
Applied Physics there Quantum
technologies that are being being uh you
know Quantum Computing is becoming a
thing now obviously there is significant
advancement happening there you have
artificial intelligence which is growing
in Leaps and Bounds not technology
whatnot so applied sciences are doing
well but the bleeding edge of science
The Cutting Edge of science which is
theoretical physics which is is about
our understanding of the universe is
there's no progress there there are
these gigantic Mysteries sitting out
there that we aren't able to uh you know
make any progress on so that is the
situation
okay okay inia says why why are the
international media and some Indian
YouTubers mocking the luxurious Amani
wedding ceremony you said that money is
power then why the media are not in in
their
favor I have never said money is power I
have said the opposite money cannot buy
you power but Power can buy you more
money please pay
attention Okay money cannot buy you
power you may be have you may have as
much money as you can imagine it can't
buy you power but if you are powerful
you can acquire as much money as you
want that's how it works now the qu the
main question you're asking is why has
the international media and some Indian
YouTubers why have they been mocking the
luxurious wedding ceremony because
they're jealous because they don't like
to see anyone succeed the ambanis if
they have succeeded and become so
wealthy well they have done it through
their hard work and their abilities
right they haven't stolen anyone's money
there is this view in India that for
someone to get rich others need to get
poor why do people see the world that
way when you become wealthy when you
become rich you create more wealth for
others you generate employment for
thousands of people why don't you see it
that way this wedding in which they
spent I don't know how many millions of
dollars imagine how much employment this
wedding
ceremony
generated it must have generated
generated so much employment so many
purchase orders so many staff must have
come so many people must have come to
cater for this or that or whatever so
much employment and business must have
been generated and the ambanis if they
spent let's say $100 million I'm just
assuming I have no idea how much they
spent okay but assume hypothetically
they spent $100 million that money went
here there everywhere into various
people's businesses right isn't that
good for the economy I just don't get
these people these narrow-minded people
they hate wealth and prosperity they
want everyone to remain poor I think we
should celebrate people who succeed and
become rich because they've done so
through their own hard work and their
talent and their Merit their sweat and
Blood and Tears they haven't stolen
anyone's
money so yeah it's just jealousy it's
just jealousy that mediocre people have
against the ones who are truly capable I
would say we should be happy that such
things are happening in India I'm
glad dunger sing Johan says you said
that the Japanese people are not aware
of them being proxies or a colony of the
US how can this be possible they are
well connected to the outside world
through social media please
clarify tell me something how many
people apart from me say this openly
that Japan is under us colon under US
military
occupation if you look at the world's
media if you look at uh BBC CNN they
portra Japan as a democracy right
because you have elections and you have
Prime Ministers who are who come to
office and then there are coalitions and
then they they lose power and then
somebody else is elected there's a
wonderful vibrant Democratic process
happening right in Japan that's how
Japan is portrayed Japan is portrayed as
this big uh economic power which is now
stagnating obviously and so on and the
bank of Japan apparently is responsible
for that but nobody ever mentions the
fact there are more than 130 us
permanent Mill
bases on Japanese territory who mentions
that and some Japanese will be aware of
it because see the thing about Japan is
that the Americans have turned Japan
into Disneyland into their place where
they go for vacation so at any given
point in time in Japan there are tens of
thousands of Americans on vacation and
there are soldiers also okay with
because they have so many military
bases but the way it is portrayed is
that these are joint
operations between the US and Japan and
the US and Japan are close treaty allies
because they have signed treaties
unfortunately okay Alliance so the
treaties are worded in such a manner
that makes it look like these are
Alliance this is an alliance and the
Japanese government is willingly asking
the Americans to set up military bases
on Japanese soil to protect Japan so the
language that has been used in all these
treaties and all that is such that it
looks like it's an alliance and not an
occupation
and that's what is taught to the
Japanese people and that's what is told
to the whole
world so forget about the Japanese if
you ask people from other countries is
anyone aware that the Americans are
occupying Japan nobody sees it that way
and because there is no brutality there
are no atrocities on the Japanese people
so it's not visible at all it's only in
Uka that the Japanese people complain
about the
tremendously heavy occupation of the
island and of of course the American GIS
there have been doing certain
things again to the to the population
which uh which is kind of you can look
upon it as
atrocities um so it's in Okinawa that a
little bit of uh protesting has been
happening but apart from that nowhere
else so because of this overall
situation it's very well choreographed
very well
managed that nobody understands what's
really happening even Italy is under us
occupation do you know that does any
Italian ever say say that anywhere in
the world that our nation is under us
occupation does any German say is any
German aware of the fact that they are
under us occupation nobody's aware
because the their their own government
their own media their own education
system is confiscating the
truth so yeah that's how it is it is
very much possible that people are not
aware of what's happening to it to them
even in India we don't know that we are
colonized we are still
colonized how can this be possible that
no Indian knows that they are mentally
colonized of course it's possible of
course it's
true all
right okay uh shall I take one more
question
perhaps
[Music]
um Aram Mana says what's your views on
South Korea's recent robot suicide news
I haven't seen this news robot suicide
really a robot committed
suicide but robots aren't alive right
right they're just
machines I don't know I I have to look
it up I was not aware of this robot
suicide why why did did it commit
suicide shall I look it up quickly let
me look it up and let's put that on the
screen robot suicide that's
weird South sorry South Korea
[Music]
robot news what
happened uh robots Su said robots civil
servant South Korea
was found unresponsive at the bottom of
a
stairwell commit suicide because it was
what it was made to do a lot of work
really B shatter the blah blah blah blah
blah blah
Etc was look I don't know maybe the
media is making a mountain out of a mole
hill maybe the robot had an accident and
it fell down or whatever and the media
is saying it's a suicide you know the
term Big Bang
was coined by the media okay it wasn't
coined by any physicist the media has
this habit of blowing things out of
proportion I will read this in detail
and if it's really interesting I'll
speak about it again so I don't have any
views right now because I've just seen
the news I I've seen it here in this
question but I'll check it
out okay
um
uh is there any other question I can
take
in
um um maheswar okay this is the last
question for today physics question um
maheswari says what is tunneling effect
and what and can we go subatomic if we
really reduce the size of an atom if not
the space between them
uh you can't reduce the size of an atom
it's simply unphysical to do that okay
there is no way you can do it the laws
of phys physics don't allow that to
happen everything all subatom
fundamental particles subatomic
particles have certain sizes and certain
things so you can't mess with that okay
so you can't go subatomic now what's the
tunneling effect look there's a wall
behind me if I throw a ball at the wall
what's going to happen it's going to hit
the wall and bounce back right so that's
how the normal World behaves if I throw
something at the TV screen behind me
it's going to bounce off the TV screen
and come back to me right a ball let's
say but in the quantum world what's the
quantum world it is this it is the ultra
microscopic World okay look at this
microphone the formo here you go deep
into it you go to the atomic level
that's the quantum world that's the
quantum domain the quantum domain of the
world we inhabit so everything that we
see all the light all the physical
properties of everything we are familiar
with all of that emerges from the ultra
microscopic level and that's a Quantum
level at the quantum level the laws of
physics are extremely different so if
you have a wall and if you have a
particle going hitting the wall there is
a nonzero probability that the particle
will just go through the wall tunnel
through it and that is quantum tunneling
that's the tunneling effect you can
measure the probability of of a particle
tunneling through a barrier and when you
start learning quantum mechanics the
ABCs of quantum mechanics that's the
exercises you do problems tunneling you
know potentials and tunneling and all so
that is the tunneling effect in the
quantum World a ball a tennis ball ball
a Quantum tennis ball can actually pass
through a Quantum wall That's how weird
the quantum world is and it gives rise
to the world that we are familiar with
so that is the teling effect all right
ladies gentlemen's friends thank you so
much for all your questions was great
okay Costo is saying bookshelf tour will
happen soon I'm I'm in the process of
rearranging everything it'll happen soon
thank you for the reminder so thank you
so much for all your questions it was
great to be back back live amongst all
of you and the next episode is tomorrow
in which I will take questions that
you've asked in the comments and also
some live questions so until tomorrow 22
hours from now I'll take you leave and
I'll see you very soon thank you so much
for your viewership for your questions
and don't forget to keep raising your
standards thank you so much I'll see you
soon bye